Charles Cook

Electrician

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Charles-Cook/4ed7870a050aaeea

An experienced electrician with more than ten years of commercial and residential experience. With background in installing, maintaining, and repairing electrical wiring, equipment, and fixtures, ensuring that work is in accordance with relevant codes; installing and servicing street lights, intercom systems, and electrical control systems. Knowledgeable in all areas of the national electrical code; and excel in analyzing and solving problems with various electrical controls and systems.

Hilti Gun Certification:

- * Ability to run Trenchers, Backhoes & Bucket Trucks
- * Install 100A & 200A Services and Sheet Rock

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mechanical Engineer

Rittenhouse Condominiums & Hotel - Philadelphia, PA - 2015 to Present

Responsibilities

Take readings an check amperage for all mechanical rooms twice a day. Handle any Plumbing, Electrical, HVAC,problems in Condos & building. Record all work order in to computer data base daliy.

Sign Technician

Icon - 2013 to 2015

Responsibilities

Icon Sign Company

Sign Technician (2013-2015)

- Installed LED lighting circuit boards signs. Morristown, NJ
- Installed and replaced mental high light transformers and ballist.
- Completed work task and have familiarity with routes in the tri-state franchisers (Best Buy, Walgreens, Rite-Aide, and CVS)
- Independently operated 41-foot bucket trucks to service parking lot lights, commercial building & signs.

Electrician

Blige Electric - Philadelphia, PA - 2006 to 2012

- Served as electrician an apprentice on more than 400 new home construction projects as well as dozens of major commercial projects.
- Earned a reputation for expertise in complex troubleshooting and problem resolution.
- Gained extensive experience in analyzing and following manuals, schematic diagrams, blueprints and other specifications.
- Mastered the use of measuring/testing instruments such as ammeters, ohmmeters, voltmeters and testing lamps.
- Consistently commended for team-player mind-set, "doing it right the first time" and working with minimal supervision under tight deadlines.

• Prepare sketches or follow blueprints to determine the location of wiring and equipment and to ensure conformance to building and safety codes.

Electrical Apprentice

G.C.W. Electric - Philadelphia, PA - 2005 to 2006

- Installed, adjusted, modified, verified, calibrated and tested operation of power systems, specialized electrical systems and panels, circuitry, electrical chassis, appliances, portable electrical equipment in accordance with all State and Federal Electrical Codes and Ordinances.
- Able to work from verbal instructions, blueprints, wiring diagrams, schematics, technical publications and instructions bulletins.
- Performed corrective repairs on commercial and residential buildings. Factory electrical maintenance and repair and installation.
- Can direct work of and instruct other electricians, helpers, mechanics and apprentices.
- Repaired AC/DC circuits, 3-phase circuits (480 and 240 volt)

Lighting Technician

Philadelphia Lighting - Philadelphia, PA - 2003 to 2005

- Assemble, install, test, and maintain electrical or electronic wiring, equipment, appliances, apparatus, and fixtures, using hand tools and power tools.
- Connect wires to circuit breakers, transformers, or other components.
- Place conduit (pipes or tubing) inside designated partitions, walls, or other concealed areas, and pull insulated wires or cables through the conduit to complete circuits between boxes.
- Perform physically demanding tasks, such as digging trenches to lay conduit and moving and lifting heavy objects.
- Experienced in industrial equipment repair including motor controls (AC & DC), electrical print reading and interpretations, trouble shooting of control systems, and electric devices for high speed packaging/processing equipment.
- Basic experience in troubleshooting PLC's

EDUCATION

Diploma

Orleans Technical Institute - Philadelphia, PA 2003 to 2004

High School Diploma

Germantown High School - Philadelphia, PA 1995 to 1999

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Technical Competencies:

- · Mathematics and Blueprint Reading
- Electrical Measuring Devices
- Residential Wiring Systems
- AC Theory, Electrical Motors
- Controllers and PLCs
- Commercial Wiring Systems